Quentin Moreno-Gelos

PROFILE

Theoretical physicist with over 8 years of extensive research experience in theoretical and computational plasma physics. My expertise lies in developing innovative theoretical models and performing complex simulations to understand plasma behavior in both laboratory and astrophysical environments.

CONTACT DETAILS

@ moreno_quentin@numericable.fr

+33 628 480 516

Portfolio

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Citizenship: French
Family: Single without children
Languages: French (native),
English (fluent), , Spanish
(Intermediate)

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- Python
- SOL
- PowerBI
- fortran95
- Mathematica
- LaTeX
- MS Word, Excel, PowerPoint

SCIENTIFIC EXPERTISE

- Plasma Instabilities
- Shock formation
- Laser plasma interaction
- Kinetic Particle-in-cell code (SMILEI/EPOCH)
- Magneto-hydrodynamic AMR code (FLASH)
- Machine learning

EXPERIENCE

POSTDOCTORAL FELLOW at ELI-beamlines

2019.01-2023.12

- Theoretical studies on radiative/adiabatic shocks in a context relevant to laboratory astrophysics.
 - Designed analytical self-similar models.
 - Realized Magneto-Hydrodynamic AMR simulations on large supercalculators.
 - Created AMR simulations data visualization tools (matplotlib).
 - Analyzed large datasets to confront analytical models with numerical simulations.
 - Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design complex laboratory experiment to assess effectiveness of analytical models.
 - Published findings in peer-reviewed journals and presented at international conferences.
- Onducted numerical analysis to support various research projects.
- ♦ Supervised a first year master student during 3 months.

PHD STUDENT at Bordeaux University.

2015.10-2018.12

- ♦ Theoretical studies on plasma instabilities that can lead to collisionless shocks in a context relevant to laboratory astrophysics.
 - · Designed analytical models.
 - Realized Particle-In-Cell (PIC) simulations on large supercalculators.
 - Created PIC simulations data visualization tools (matplotlib).
 - Analyzed large datasets to confront analytical models with numerical simulations.
 - Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design complex laboratory experiment to assess effectiveness of analytical models.
 - Published findings in peer-reviewed journals and presented at international conferences.
- Course examiner at Bordeaux University
 - Teaching experience from Bachelor to master degree.

PUBLICATIONS

- \$\delta\$ 13 publications in peer-reviewed journals
- h-index: 7 (from researchgate)

EDUCATION AT BORDEAUX UNIVERSITY

DOCTORAL DEGREE: Astrophysics, plasma and nuclear **2015–2018** Thesis title: *Non-relativistic collisionless shocks in Laboratory Astrophysics.*

MASTER'S DEGREE: Theoretical physics

2013-2015

Astrophysics, Statistical physics, numerical methods

BACHELOR'S DEGREE: Theoretical physics

2010-2013